Finding Aid for Frederick Maltby Warner papers, 1832-1918
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frederick Maltby Warner papers 1832-1918
Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.
1.5 linear feet and 1 oversize folder
86206 Aa 2; Ac
Republican governor of Michigan, 1905-1910. Account books, and legal and business papers of P. Dean Warner, Oakland County, Michigan, farmer and cheese manufacturer; and political scrapbooks and other papers of his adopted son, Fred M. Warner, largely concerning election campaigns; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The bulk of the collection came from Mrs. Fred M. Warner (donor no. 879 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Fred Maltby Warner was born July 21, 1854, in Hickling, Nottinghamshire, England. After coming to the United States and following the death of his mother, Warner was adopted by P.Dean Warner of Farmington in Oakland County. He attended Michigan Agricultural College for a year, then worked in his father's store. In 1889, Warner started a cheese business which eventually encompassed twelve different factories in Oakland County. He also became involved in dairy farming and banking, being a stockholder and director of the Farmington Exchange Bank.
Warner served two terms in the Michigan Senate, 1895-1898. He also served two terms as Secretary of State 1901-1905. Warner was elected governor in 1904 and re-elected in 1906 and 1908. He died April 17, 1923.
The Fred M. Warner papers include papers of P. Dean Warner and Fred M. Warner. Included are letters, legal documents, business papers, a volume recording customers of Warner's cheese business, and scrapbooks. Except for a few folders relating to aid given to California following the 1906 earthquake, there are few documents relating to Warner's terms as governor.
Subjects:
Business records.; Cheese.; Farmers--Michigan--Oakland County.; Michigan--Politics and government--1877-1898.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Oakland County (Mich.); Republican Party (Mich.); Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.; Governors--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Automobiles.; Farmington (Mich.)--Food industry.; Fred M. Warner Cheese Company. Powers Factory No. 11 (Farmington, Mich.); Food industry--Michigan--Farmington.; Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.
Contributors:
Warner, P. Dean (Pascal Dean), 1822-1910.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Family and P. Dean Warner Papers
  - Miscellaneous family papers, 1832 and 1846 (Box 1)
  - P. Dean Warner
    - Correspondence, 1866, 1879 and 1890-1905 (Box 1)
    - European diary, 1878
      - Original (Box 1)
      - Typescript (Box 1)
    - Legal documents
      - 1858-1890 (Box 1)
      - 1891-1910 (Box 1)
    - Receipts (Box 1)
    - Statements, accounts and financial materials (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Cash book, 1881-1895 (Box 1)
    - Book: A System of Natural Philosophy ... (1840) (Box 1)
- Fred M. Warner
  - Correspondence (with father and other friends and relatives)
    - Undated and 1874-1875 (Box 1)
    - 1876 (Box 1)
    - 1877-1878 (Box 1)
    - 1879 (Box 1)
    - January-September 1880 (Box 1)
    - October-December 1880 (Box 1)
    - 1881-1885 (Box 1)
    - 1919-1922 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (gubernatorial)
    - California Relief, undated and April-September 1906, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - General, 1906-1909 (Box 1)
  - Genealogical and biographical material (Box 1)
  - Guardianship and estate Materials, 1909-1911 (Box 1)
  - Legal documents, 1907-1918, 1916, 1920, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Receipts and accounts (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous; include business cards (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous; include business advertisements (Box 1)
  - Minute book-Warner Dairy, 1907-1956 (Box 1)
  - Record of cheese customers by county name, 1906 (Box 1)
  - School notebooks, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Photograph of Warner in automobile outside the Fred M. Warner Cheese Company (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 4 volumes
    - Political, July-November 1903 (Box 2)
    - Board of State Auditors and Board of Equalization, 1901-1902 (Box 2)
    - Personal: Cheese Village and Dairymen's Association, 1900-1903 (Box 2)
    - Campaign and election notices, 1900-1903 (Box 2)
    - 1900-1903, 4 volumes (Box 2)
  - Clippings (Box 2)
  - Certificates and miscellaneous (Folder 1)